Guide to "Yale Reports" Audio Recordings and Transcripts
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
"Yale Reports" Audio Recordings and Transcripts
1955-1976
RU 1113
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
74.75
(248 boxes)
The material consists of audio recordings, transcriptions, and press releases regarding broadcasts of Yale Reports, a series of radio programs produced by the Yale University News Bureau. The programs featured Yale professors and guests discussing contemporary issues from 1955 to 1976.
Yale University. News Bureau
Scope and Contents
The material consists of audio recordings, transcriptions, and press releases regarding broadcasts of Yale Reports, a series of radio programs produced by the Yale University News Bureau. The programs featured Yale professors and guests discussing contemporary issues from 1955 to 1976.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series: I. Audio Recordings, 1955-1976. II. Transcripts, 1955-1970, 1975. III. Press Releases, 1962-1966.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 4-C (YRG 4-C), Office of Public Affairs.
Custodial History
Transferred from Historical Sound Recordings, 2011.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Yale University. News Bureau
- Audio Recordings, 1956-1976; Series I; The audiotapes are 5.5" and 7.5" reel-to-reel.
  Arrangement
  The audiotapes are arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - "Papers of Great Men" I, 1956 January 8; 1 (Box 1)
  - "The Papers of James Boswell", 1956 January 15; 1 (Box 2)
  - "The Papers of Benjamin Franklin", 1956 January 22; 1 (Box 3)
  - "Understanding Child Development", 1956 January 29; 1 (Box 4)
  - "Child Development: Nursery School", 1956 February 12; 1 (Box 5)
  - "Responsibilities of Alumni", 1956 February 19; 1 (Box 6)
  - "Modern Ireland", 1956 April 1; 1 (Box 7)
  - "Teaching Creative Writing", 1956 April 15; 1 (Box 8)
  - "Rebecca West & Ralph Brown", 1956 May 13; 1 (Box 9)
  - "Colleges & Amateur Athletics" I, 1956 September 16; 1 (Box 10)
  - "Colleges & Amateur Athletics" II, 1956 September 23; 1 (Box 11)
  - "Theater in a University" I, 1956 October 28; 1 (Box 12)
  - "Theater in a University" II", 1956 November 4; 1 (Box 13)
  - "Theater in a University" III, 1956 November 11; 1 (Box 14)
  - "Scholars view Soviet Russia", 1956 November 18; 1 (Box 15)
  - "The Teaching of Art" I-III, 1957 January 13, 20, 27; 1 (Box 16)
  - "Planning and the Urban Region", 1957 February 24; 1 (Box 17)
  - "City Planning: the Atlantic Region", 1957 March 3; 1 (Box 18)
  - "Can Planning Stop Destruction?", 1957 March 10; 1 (Box 19)
  - "Music as a Profession", 1957 March 17; 1 (Box 20)
  - "Training for Music Profession", 1957 March 24; 1 (Box 21)
  - "Music in College", 1957 March 31; 1 (Box 22)
  - "Music in Secondary School", 1957 April 7; 1 (Box 23)
  - "What is Man? (Theologian's View)", 1957 April 14; 1 (Box 24)
  - "Interview with Clement Attlee", 1957 May 12; 1 (Box 25)
  - "Is There Still Hope for Poetry?", 1957 May 19; 1 (Box 26)
  - "Poetry and Thinking", 1957 May 26; 1 (Box 27)
  - "Student Views College Requirements", 1957 September 29; 1 (Box 28)
  - "Student View Last College Years", 1957 October 13; 1 (Box 29)
  - "The Science of Ornithology", 1957 October 20; 1 (Box 30)
  - "Britain's Educational Picture", 1957 October 27; 1 (Box 31)
  - "Britain's Education & Social Change", 1957 November 3; 1 (Box 32)
  - "Modern French Literature", 1957 December 8; 1 (Box 33)
  - "Modern French Literature: Camus", 1957 December 15; 1 (Box 34)
  - "Undergraduate, Uncommitted, Lonely", 1957 December 22; 1 (Box 35)
  - "The College Chaplain", 1957 December 29; 1 (Box 36)
  - "Interview with Margaret Mead", 1958 January 12; 1 (Box 37)
  - "The Many Facets of Anthropology", 1958 January 19; 1 (Box 38)
  - "Geology: the Earth's Surface", 1958 February 9; 1 (Box 39)
  - "College Singing" I, 1958 March 2; 1 (Box 40)
  - "College Singing" II, 1958 March 9; 1 (Box 41)
  - "The Angry Young Men & the English Novel", Johnson, Pamela Hansford, 1958 March 14; 1 (Box 42)
  - "African Studies" I, 1958 March 30; 1 (Box 43)
  - "African Studies" II, 1958 April 6; 1 (Box 44)
  - "African Studies" III, 1958 April 13; 1 (Box 45)
  - "Mathematics" I, 1958 April 20; 1 (Box 46)
  - "Mathematics in College", 1958 April 27; 1 (Box 47)
  - "Interview with Mary McCarthy", 1958 May 11; 1 (Box 48)
  - "American Studies" I, 1958 May 25; 1 (Box 49)
  - "American Studies" II, 1958 June 1; 1 (Box 50)
  - "American Studies" III, 1958 June 8; 1 (Box 51)
  - "What is Psychiatry?" I, 1958 September 21; 1 (Box 52)
  - "The Role of Psychiatry in the Modern World" III, 1958 October 5; 1 (Box 53)
  - "The Place of Psychiatry in the Modern World" IV, 1958 October 12; 1 (Box 54)
  - "The American Dilemma", 1958 November 16; 1 (Box 55)
  - "Crises of an Age Reflect in Art", 1958 November 23; 1 (Box 56)
  - "The Angry Young Men", 1958 November 30; 1 (Box 57)
  - "Parkinson's Law an Academic Admin", 1958 December 21; 1 (Box 58)
  - "Philosophies of Today IV", 1959 March 29; 1 (Box 59)
  - "Athletics" Mr Red Smith, Mr D. Kiphuth, Mr B. Kiphuth, Mrs E. Kerr, 1959 April 19; 1 (Box 60)
  - "The Role of America's Loyal Opposition", 1959 May 3; 1 (Box 61)
  - "Art and Architecture" III, 1959 May 24; 1 (Box 62)
  - "Art and Architecture" IV, 1959 May 31; 1 (Box 63)
  - "Art and Architecture" V, 1959 June 7; 1 (Box 64)
  - "Conversation with Iris Murdoch", 1959 November 1; 1 (Box 65)
  - "Operation Crossroads Africa" I, Mr. W.S. Coffin, Mrs. E. Kerr, 1960 December 25; 1 (Box 66)
  - Chester Bowles, 1961 November 21; 1 (Box 67)
  - "National Purpose" III, Mr. A MacLeish, Mrs W.P. Bundy, Mrs E. Kerr, Circa 1961; 1 (Box 68)
  - [No Title], Mr J. Lindsay, Mr J.M. Blum, Mrs E. Kerr, Circa 1961; 1 (Box 69)
  - "Man and Society in the European Novel" IV, Mr R.W.B. Lewis, Mr V. Brombert, Mrs E. Kerr, Circa 1961; 1 (Box 70)
  - "The Image of the Hero in French Fiction" V, Mr V. Brombert, Mr R.W.B. Lewis, Mrs E. Kerr, Circa 1961; 1 (Box 71)
  - "The Anti-Hero in the American Novel" III, Mr L. Fiedler, Mr R.W.B. Lewis, Mrs E. Kerr, Circa 1961; 1 (Box 72)
  - "The Church and Civil Rights", Rev William S. Coffin, Jr, 1962 January 12; 1 (Box 73)
  - "The Law and Civil Rights", Rev. William S. Coffin, Jr., 1962 January 19; 1 (Box 74)
  - "A Conservative Speaks" I, Sen B. Goldwater, Mr. J. Rose, Mrs. E. Kerr, 1962 April 19; 1 (Box 75)
  - "A Conservative Speaks" II, Sen B. Goldwater, Mr. J. Rose, Mrs. E. Kerr, 1962 April 27; 1 (Box 76)
  - "Role of the Government in the Arts" II, Mr. G.A. Danes, Mr. A.C. Ritchie, Mrs. A. Saarinen, Mrs. E. Kerr, 1962 June 1; 1 (Box 77)
  - "Old Christmas Music", Mr Fenno Heath, Circa 1962; 1 (Box 78)
  - "Law School Forum" (Law School Auditorium), Nov 29, 1962, Arthur Schlesinger Jr, Richard E. Neustadt, Sidney Hyman, Bryce N. Harlow, Denis W. Brogan., 1963 February 10; 1 (Box 81)
  - "Law School Forum" (Law School Auditorium), Nov 29, 1962, Arthur Schlesinger Jr, Richard E. Neustadt, Sidney Hyman, Bryce N. Harlow, Denis W. Brogan., 1963 February 17; 1 (Box 82)
  - "Responsible Nuclear Policy", Mr. McGeorge Bundy, 1963 February 16; 1 (Box 82A)
  - "Conflict in the Shadows", Mr J. Cross, Col. R. Heinl, Mr W.R. Emerson, Mrs S. Hough, 1963 March 24; 1 (Box 83)
  - "The Role of a Literary Critic", Mar 31, 1963, Mr W.K. Wimsatt Jr, Mr H. Peyre, Mrs S. Hough, 1963 March 31; 1 (Box 84)
  - John Blum, John Lindsay, 1963 April 5; 1 (Box 85)
  - "Plays and Playwrights", Mr E.M. Waith, Mr J.W. Gassner, Mrs S. Hough, 1963 April 7; 1 (Box 86)
  - "Contemporary Films", Dwight Macdonald, L. Livingston, T. Mankiewicz, S. Hough, 1963 April 14; 1 (Box 87)
  - "A Political Dialogue", John Blum, John Lindsay, 1963 April 28; 1 (Box 88)
  - "Interview with Douglas Dillon", Mr D. Dillon, Mr L.G. Reynolds, Mr J.H. van Merkensteijn, 1963 May 5; 1 (Box 89)
  - "A Political Philosophy", Ignazio Silone, Victor Brombert, Sergio Pacifici, Edgar Pauk (interpreter), 1963 June 2; 1 (Box 90)
  - Mr Chermayoff, "From the other end of the spectrum", Reel 1, 1963 December 11[?] / 1964 January 19[?]; 1 (Box 91)
  - "Existentialism & Psychotherapy", II, Mr J. Wild, Mr R. May, Mr G. Schrader, Mrs S. Hough, 1963 December 15; 1 (Box 92)
  - "Portrait of an Artist", Nov 13, 1963, Edwin Dickinson, Louis Finklestein, 1964 January 12; 1 (Box 93)
  - "On Modern Art", Jack Tworkov, Sumner Crosby, Bernard Chaet, Tom Susman, 1964 March 15; 1 (Box 94)
  - "Dialogue on Democracy", M.P. Mendes-France, David Calleo, 1964 March 29; 1 (Box 95)
  - "Man made America: Chaos or Control", Christopher Tunnard, Boris Pushkarev, Sheila Hough, 1964 April 5; 1 (Box 96)
  - "The University and the National Government", Kingman Brewster Jr, Davidson Nicol, Jaime Benitez, 1964 April 12; 1 (Box 97)
  - "The Philosopher as Critic", Mr Herbert Marcuse, Mr Richard Berstein, Mrs S. Hough, 1964 April 26; 1 (Box 98)
  - "New Evidence on the Origin of Man", Mr Louis S.B. Leakey, Mrs S. Hough, Mr Elwyn L. Simons, Mr John Buettner-Janusch, 1964 May 7[?] / 1964 May 10[?]; 1 (Box 100)
  - "Five Days in April", Mr Frederick March, Mrs Frederick March (Mrs), Miss C. Welch, 1964 May 17; 1 (Box 101)
  - "The Critic and the Arts", Father W.J. Ong, Mr W.K. Wimsatt, Mrs S. Hough, 1964 May 24; 1 (Box 102)
  - "On Poetry", Robert Duncan, Eugene Vance, Dave Schaff, 1964 May 31; 1 (Box 103)
  - "Music in the Yale Tradition", Fenno Heath Jr., 1964 June 14; 1 (Box 104)
  - "Is Civil Disobedience Ever Justified?", Prof Alexander Bickel, Prof Alexander d'Entreves, Rev William Sloane Coffin Jr, Mrs S. Hough, 1964 October 25; 1 (Box 105)
  - "The Role of Law in American Society", Prof Alexander Bickel, Prof Alexander d'Entreves, Rev William Sloane Coffin Jr, Mrs S. Hough, 1964 November 1; 1 (Box 106)
  - "What is History", Mr P. Weiss, Mr P. Smith, Mrs S. Hough, 1964 November 15; 1 (Box 107)
  - "Position of a Southern Governor", Governor Terry Sanford, [Additional names indecipherable], 1964 December 6; 1 (Box 108)
  - "The Nature of Historical Evidence", Prof H.R. Trevor-Roper, Prof Joseph LaPalomabara, Mrs Sheila Hough, 1965 January 17; 1 (Box 109)
  - "The American Woman", Mrs E.G. Rostow, Dr R.J. Lifton, Mrs S. Hough, 1965 January 24; 1 (Box 110)
  - "Great Moments in Modern American Oratory 1896-1951", Mr R.G. Osterweis, Mrs. S. Hough, 1965 February 7; 1 (Box 111)
  - "Man and the Machine" I, Mr. K. Brewster Jr, 1964 February 14; 1 (Box 112)
  - "Man and the Machine" II, Mr. R.P. Abelson, Mr. E.E. Morison, 1965 February 21; 1 (Box 113)
  - "Creativity I", Dr R. May, Mr. K. Keniston, Mrs S. Hough, 1965 March 7; 1 (Box 114)
  - "Creativity II", Dr R. May, Mr. K. Keniston, Mrs S. Hough, 1965 March 14; 1 (Box 115)
  - "A View from the Hill", John V. Lindsay, John M. Blum, 1965 March 21; 1 (Box 116)
  - "An Unorthodox Look at Smoking", Mr J. Hollander, Mr W. Styren, Dr D.X. Freedman, Mrs S. Hough, 1965 April 4; 1 (Box 117)
  - "Paris in the Twenties", Miss Kay Boyle, 1965 April 25; 1 (Box 118)
  - "Singing at Yale", Fenno Heath, 1965 May 9; 1 (Box 119)
  - "Utopias" George Kateb, John Hollander, Marshall Cohen, Mrs Sheila Hough, 1965 June 6; 1 (Box 120)
  - "Austria: Problems of Neutrality", Mr. Bruno Kreisky, Mr Howard S. Weaver, Mr Richard L. Merritt, 1965 October 31; 1 (Box 121)
  - "Vinland Map Discovery", Mr. J. Levitch, Mr. J.R. Tanis, Mr. T.E. Marston, Mr. A.O. Vietor, 1965 November 21; 1 (Box 122)
  - "Yale Drama School Fortieth Anniversary, Nov 6, 1965; The Next 40 Years of American Theater" I, A. Albee, J. Mielziner, 1965 November 28; 1 (Box 123)
  - "Yale Drama School Fortieth Anniversary, Nov 6, 1965; The Next 40 Years of American Theater" II, Mr M. Carnovsky, Mr A. Schnider, 1965 December 5; 1 (Box 124)
  - "Saying the Unthinkable" I, Mr C.V. Woodward, Mr J. Barnes, Mr W. Uphans, 1966 January 2; 1 (Box 125)
  - "Saying the Unthinkable" II, Mr C.V. Woodward, Mr W. Uphans, Mr C. Durr, 1966 January 9; 1 (Box 126)
  - "The Art of Latin America since Independence", Mr S.L. Catlin, Mr T.R. Griedev, Mr D. Davidson, Mr G.A. Kubler, 1966 January 16; 1 (Box 128)
  - "The Mass News Media and Criminal Justice" II, Mel Elfin, Gerald R. Ford, Gabriel Pressman, 1965 May 23; 1 (Box 129)
  - "Mayor Wagner Discusses New York City", Mayor R.F. Wagner Jr, Mr H. Kaufman, Mr J.G. Simon, 1966 April 24; 1 (Box 130)
  - "Ralph McGill: a Journalist, a Southerner", Mr R. McGill, Mr C. Vann Woodward, Mr J.H. Rothchild, 1966 May 1; 1 (Box 131)
  - "Recent French Policies under De Gaulle", Amb. C. Lucet, Mr D.P. Calleo, Mr H. Peyre, 1966 May 8; 1 (Box 132)
  - "Problems of Poverty", Mr R.S. Shriver, Mr W.L. Miller, Mr M. Sviridoff., 1966 May 15; 1 (Box 133)
  - "Theatre: Amenity or Necessity", Mr Tyrone Guthrie, 1966 May 22; 1 (Box 134)
  - "A Critic Looks at the Theatre Today", Mr H. Taubman, Mr R. Murray, Mr R.M. Benard, 1966 May 29; 1 (Box 135)
  - "Obscenity and the First Amendment", Mr L.H. Pollak, Mr R.M. Dworkin, Mr J. Hollander, 1966 June 19; 1 (Box 136)
  - "Selecting Freshman: the Awesome Task of American Colleges", Mr K. Brewster Jr, Mr R.I. Clark Jr, Mr L.M. Noble, Group of Alumni and Guidance Counsellors, 1966 October 2; 1 (Box 137)
  - "Nuclear Art and Architecture", Mr A.W. Galston, Mr D.A. Bromley, 1966 December 11; 1 (Box 138)
  - "The Midwife, the Witch and Modern Medicine", 1967 February 5; 1 (Box 139)
  - "Attitudes of the Combat Soldiers", Mr C.C. Moskos Jr, Mr N.W. Polsby, Mr W. Bell, 1967 March 5; 1 (Box 140)
  - "God, Man, and Technology" I, Mr E. Mesthene, Mr. H. Clark, Mr C. Tunnard, Mr. C. Argyris, Mr M. McCulloch, 1967 April 23; 1 (Box 141)
  - "God, Man, and Technology" II, Mr E. Mesthene, Mr. H. Clark, Mr C. Tunnard, Mr. C. Argyris, Mr M. McCulloch, Mr K. Deutsch, 1967 April 30; 1 (Box 142)
  - "Why Cheer a Loser?", Mr H. Chauncey Jr, Mr P. Weiss, Mr D. Kiphuth, 1967 May 14; 1 (Box 143)
  - "Encountering Marc Chagall", Mr J.E.H. Guicharnaud, Mr H.E. Krawitz, 1967 June 11; 1 (Box 144)
  - "Randall Jarrell Remembered by His Friends", Mr P. Taylor, Mr R. Lowell, Mr J. Berryman, Mr S. Kunitz, 1967 June 25; 1 (Box 145)
  - "Trouble in the Streets: New Haven was not Immune" Part I, Rev Raymond Shulze, Rev G. Gilmore, Mr & Mrs W. Bradley, Mr R. Jordan, Mrs J Russell, Dr Max Pepper, J. Boyles (narrator), 1967 October 1; 1 (Box 146)
  - "Trouble in the Streets: New Haven was not Immune" Part II, Rev J. Boyles, Rev G. Gilmore, Mr & Mrs W. Bradley, Mr R. Jordan, Mrs J Russell, Dr Max Pepper, 1967 October 8; 1 (Box 147)
  - "The Human Animal", Mr J. Bronowski, Mr A.W. Galston, 1967 October 29; 1 (Box 148)
  - "Light and Leaden Verse", Mr B.C. [C.B.?] Hogan, Mr R.E. Kuehn, 1967 December 31; 1 (Box 149)
  - "Our Children's Burden: School Desegregation", Mr W. Bell, Mr K.T. Erikson, Mr R. Mack, 1968 January 7; 1 (Box 150)
  - "de Gaulle Defended", Mr R.A. Dahl, Mr H. Peyre, 1968 April 7; 1 (Box 151)
  - "Intellectual Underground I: Spain", Mr M. Duran, Mrs U.S. Lamb, 1968 April 28; 1 (Box 152)
  - "Creativity and the Use of Drugs", Dr Rollo May, 1968 June 2; 1 (Box 153)
  - "The Poetic Choices of Helen Chasin", Mr L.B. Braudy, Miss H. Chasin, 1968 June 23; 1 (Box 154)
  - "Ballads Brought to Life: Loving Well and Faithfully", Mr H.B. Garey, Mr A.E. Planchart, Mr L.L. Perkins, 1968 December 22; 1 (Box 155)
  - "New Music New Modes", Mr J. Cogen, Mr J.M. Drew, 1968 December 29; 1 (Box 156)
  - "Light and Leaden Verse" II, Mr R.E. Kuehn, Mr C.B. Hogan, 1969 January 12; 1 (Box 157)
  - "Candide Loudmouse, and the Undead", Mr E. Lockridge, Mr R. Wilbur, 1969 April 20; 1 (Box 158)
  - "Thinking About Women", Mrs A.A. Miskimin, Mrs M. Ellman, Mr N.H. Pearson, 1969 May 4; 1 (Box 159)
  - "The University and Revolution", Mr S. Spender, 1969 May 18; 1 (Box 160)
  - "Being Tolstoy's Daughter", Anna Tolstoy, 1969 June 15; 1 (Box 161)
  - "All of Human Society is the City", Mrs N. Gurwitt, Mr V.J. Scully, Mr J.R. Meyer, 1969 December 14; 1 (Box 162)
  - "For Jazz, Keyboard, and the Blues" Part One, Mr J.M. Drew, 1969 December 28; 1 (Box 163)
  - "For Jazz, Keyboard, and the Blues" Part Two, Mr J.M. Drew, 1970 January 4; 1 (Box 164)
  - "Child of the 21st Century", Mr W. Kessen, Dr J.P. Comer, Dr A. Meir, 1970 February 22; 1 (Box 165)
  - "Leslie Fiedler on Teaching", Mr L. Fiedler, Mr R.W.B. Lewis, 1970 May 17; 1 (Box 166)
  - "Gardens of Laundry: the Cityscapes of John Sloan", Mrs H.A. Cooper, Mrs J. Sloan, 1970 May 24; 1 (Box 167)
  - "Robert, S.J., James, and Mark: Benchley, Perelman, Thurber, and Twain", Mr B.C. [C.B.?] Hogan, Mr R.E. Keuhn, 1970 June 7; 1 (Box 168)
  - "Is TV Destroying American Culture?", Mr D. Cavett, Mr C. Amory, Mr L. Barzini, Mr J. Newfield, 1970 June 21; 1 (Box 169)
  - "Law, Society and the Nature of Man", Mr H.H. Wellington, Mr L.J. Pospisil, Mr R.L. Abel, Mr F. Snyder, 1970 October 11; 1 (Box 170)
  - "Children and Educators: the Complaints of a Curator", Mr J.D. Prown, Mr R. Strong, 1970 November 1; 1 (Box 171)
  - "A Perfection of Utopias", Mr. K. Cavander, Mr. A.P. Danzig, 1970 November 29; 1 (Box 172)
  - "Poetry from the Dispassionate Observer", Mr S. Kunitz, Mr. H. Seidman, 1971 April 11; 1 (Box 173)
  - "Thinking About Talking About the Making of Art", Mr K. Harvies, Miss B. Rose, Mr R. Lytle, 1971 April 18; 1 (Box 174)
  - "Kate Millett on Feminism", Miss Kate Millett, Mr Charles E. Levy, 1971 April 25; 1 (Box 175)
  - "America in the World: a British View", The Right Hon Ron Jenkins, Mr J. Goldsen, Mr L. Lipson, 1971 December 12; 1 (Box 176)
  - "New Harmony and All That Jazz" Part One, Mr James Drew, 1971 December 19; 1 (Box 177)
  - "New Harmony and All That Jazz" Part Two, Mr James Drew, 1971 December 26; 1 (Box 178)
  - "Ballads and Banjos from the Blue Ridge", Mr Paul Newman, 1972 January 2; 1 (Box 179)
  - "Space and the Imagination", Mr N. Mailer, Mr R. Jastrow, Mr J.C.G. Walker, Mr D. Allen, 1972 January 9; 1 (Box 180)
  - "The Changing Family: Victims of Our Own Biography", K.T. Erikson, Dr A.J. Solnit, Miss L. Nader, 1972 January 23; 1 (Box 181)
  - "Doublespy" Part One, Mr N.H. Pearson, Mrs N. Gurwitt, Mr A. Epstein, 1972 February 13; 1 (Box 182)
  - "Doublespy" Part Two, Mr N.H. Pearson, Mrs N. Gurwitt, Mr A. Epstein, 1972 February 20; 1 (Box 183)
  - "Art, Architecture, and Civilization", Mr P. Weiss, 1972 April 2; 1 (Box 184)
  - "Election 1972", Mr R.A. Dahl, Mr R.P. Abelson, Mr J.M. Blum, 1972 November 19; 1 (Box 185)
  - "Sports in America - Larger than Life", Mr T.G. Bergin, Mr W.W. Smith, Mr N. Podhoretz, 1972 November 26; 1 (Box 186)
  - "The Book and the Buck", Mr R.D. Rogers, Ms B.I. Salter, Mr A.A. Charpentier, 1972 December 3; 1 (Box 187)
  - "Much About Art is Really Social History", Mr R. Osborn, Mr R. Lynes, 1972 December 10; 1 (Box 188)
  - "Rewriting the American West", Mr H.R. Lamar, Mr A. Hanna Jr, 1972 December 17; 1 (Box 189)
  - Word to Music to Worship", Rev J.W. Cook, Mr W.R. Porter, 1972 December 24; 1 (Box 190)
  - "Light and Leaden Verse" 3rd ed, Mr C.B. Hogan, Mr R.E. Keuhn, 1973 January 14; 1 (Box 191)
  - "Monsters, Moon Maidens and a Sense of Wonder - The Nature of Science Fiction", Mr D.J. Price, Mr B. Searles, Ms S. Ley, 1973 February 18; 1 (Box 192)
  - "The World of Affection, a Field Guide by Robert Hass", Mr S. Kuntiz, Mr R. Hass, 1973 March 25; 1 (Box 193)
  - "The Presidency, the Vice Presidency and the Nation", Mr A.M. Bickel, Mr J.M. Blum, 1973 October 28; 1 (Box 194)
  - "Yes, But Does It Belong in a Museum?", Mr A. Shestack, Mr. E. Turner, 1973 December 2; 1 (Box 195)
  - "American Indian Music is Alive and Well", Mr D. McAllester, 1973 December 23; 1 (Box 196)
  - "Reality and the Inner World", Mr K. Keniston, The Rev T. Hesburgh, 1974 January 13; 1 (Box 197)
  - "Style, Usage and the Half-Life of Words", Mr R.J. Fogelin, Mr W. Zinsser, 1974 January 27; 1 (Box 198)
  - "Marya Mannes on Writing", Ms S.L. Hartt, Ms M. Mannes, 1974 February 3; 1 (Box 199)
  - "In Conversation with Senator Ervin", Mr L.H. Pollak, U.S. Senator S.J. Ervin Jr, 1974 February 24; 1 (Box 200)
  - "Light and Leaden Verse" Volume Four, Mr R.E. Keuhn, Mr B.C. [C.B.?] Hogan, 1974 March 31; 1 (Box 201)
  - "Black Preaching", The Rev G. Caldwell, The Rev L. Watts, The Rev P. Washington, 1974 April 28; 1 (Box 202)
  - Yale Reports '75, Master Tape 1, Kennedy, Steinem, Kelley, Fonda, Cox, Bradlee, 1975; 1 (Box 203)
  - Yale Reports '75, Master Tape 6, Soustelle, Bromley, Berg, 1975 February 23; 1 (Box 204)
  - Yale Reports '75, Master Tape 9, Abba Eban, Frank Press, 1975 March 16; 1 (Box 205)
  - Yale Reports '75, Master Tape 12, Dean Rusk, Jimmy Carter, 1975 April 6; 1 (Box 206)
  - Yale Reports '75, Master Tape 14, Hubert Humphery, Maura Stanton, 1975 April 20; 1 (Box 207)
  - Yale Reports '75, Master Tape 15, Joseph Alsop, William Sloan Coffin, Paul Newman, 1975 April 27; 1 (Box 208)
  - Yale Reports '75, Master Tape 17, "The Visit of the President", Golstein, Brewster, Ford, Guida, 1975 May 11; 1 (Box 209)
  - Yale Reports '75, Master Tape 19, Jackson, Wilkins, Bellecourt, Winship, Clymer, Brooks, 1975 May 25; 1 (Box 210)
  - Yale Reports '75, Master Tape 20, "Indochina: The End of an Era", Ball, Coffin, Fonda, Rusk, Humphery, 1975 June 1; 1 (Box 211)
  - Yale Reports '75, Master Tape 22, "Retrospective", Ford, Cavett, Eban, Cox, Enders, 1975 June 15; 1 (Box 212)
  - R. W. B. Lewis interview re: Edith Wharton Book, 1975 September; 1 (Box 213)
  - Yale Reports '75, Actuality Master Tape 2, 1975; 1 (Box 214)
  - Yale Reports '75, Actuality Master Tape 3, 1975; 1 (Box 215)
  - Yale Reports '75, Actuality Master Tape 5, 1975; 1 (Box 216)
  - Yale Reports '75, Actuality Master Tape 10, 1975; 1 (Box 217)
  - Yale Reports '75, Actuality Master Tape 11, 1975; 1 (Box 218)
  - Yale Reports '75, Actuality Master Tape 18, 1975; 1 (Box 219)
  - Yale Reports '75, Actuality Master Tape 21, 1975; 1 (Box 220)
  - Yale Reports '75-'76, Master Tape 2, Bundy, Elfin & R. W. B. Lewis, 1975 October 12; 1 (Box 221)
  - Yale Reports '75-'76, Master Tape 2, "ERA", Schlafly - 'DeCrow, 1976 February 22; 1 (Box 222)
  - Yale Reports '75-'76, Master Tape 5, Jones, Rolfe & Heath, 1975 November 2; 1 (Box 223)
  - Yale Reports '75-'76, Master Tape 7, Chancellor & Reagan, 1975 November 16; 1 (Box 224)
  - Yale Reports '75-'76, Master Tape 8, Wilson & Woodward, 1975 November 23; 1 (Box 225)
  - Yale Reports '75-'76, Master Tape 9, "A Conversation with William S. Coffin", 1975 November 30; 1 (Box 226)
  - Yale Reports '75-'76, Master Tape 12, Newman & Giamatti, 1975 December 21; 1 (Box 227)
  - Yale Reports '75-'76, Master Tape 15, Comer & Bronfenbrenner, 1976 January 11; 1 (Box 228)
  - Yale Reports '75-'76, Master Tape 17, "Eve on Avedon" Richard Avedon, 1976 January 25; 1 (Box 229)
  - Yale Women's Forum, 1976 January 27; 1 (Box 230)
  - Yale Reports '75-'76, Master Tape 18, Lewis & Spock, 1976 February 1; 1 (Box 231)
  - Yale Reports '75-'76, Master Tape 23, Schlesinger, 1976 March 7; 1 (Box 232)
  - Yale Reports '75-'76, Master Tape 24, DeCrow & Schlafly, 1976 March 14; 1 (Box 233)
  - Yale Reports '75-'76, Master Tape 25, Strauss & Moynihan, 1976 March 21; 1 (Box 234)
  - Yale Reports '75-'76, Master Tape 27, Young & Momaday, 1976 April 4; 1 (Box 235)